sandiego.edu 2009-11-21

# USD: USD Web Privacy and Security Statement

|    
|  | 

August 1, 2009

The University of San Diego respects your privacy.  Web servers are generally capable of collecting, storing, and analyzing a variety of information about those who visit the site.  Our goal is to keep all information collected at this website confidential and secure and to use it only for purposes for which it was intended or to improve the quality of the web service we provide. To inform you of our policies, we provide the following detailed information about our data collection processes.

In some cases, USD contracts with commercial services for specific web services, generally related to financial transactions, and links to their sites for those transactions.  If you are redirected to another site, something other than “sandiego.edu” in the URL, privacy and security are governed by the policies of those services and are documented by those sites.  We do attempt to ensure that those policies conform in general to USD’s policies, as outlined below.

## What information does USD collect on its Web site?

We collect personal information (such as name, address, phone, e-mail address) only if you provide it to us voluntarily through e-mail, registration forms, information request forms or surveys, or otherwise. Personal information is kept confidential and will not be disclosed to third parties except as may be required by law.  Credit card information and social security numbers are only collected for specific purposes where the information is required for the transaction, such as to register you in a course or program, allocate funds to a USD Campus Card account, or when we accept donations.  Any information of that nature is saved on our secure server and is only accessible to authorized employees to process payments or registrations or for other legitimate purposes.  Once processed, the information is deleted from the server.  Credit card information collected via commercial services such as CASHNet or the Verisign Payment Gateway is not stored on our server.

Cookies are pieces of information that a Web site transfers to an individual’s computer hard drive for recordkeeping purposes. Official USD Web pages will not issue "cookies" to anyone who visits those Web pages, except for the purpose of remembering log-in information or user preferences. Cookies will never store private information but will only reference such information elsewhere.  In those cases, cookies are used only to record security keys with limited lifetimes for your convenience in accessing other secured pages. USD also uses services such as Google Analytics, which will issue cookies from their own servers and which will be able to track Web site visitors throughout USD Web pages and through any other sites that use those services. USD does not control how those cookies are issued, or the data that they store. For more information about the Google Analytics privacy policy, please click here: Google Analytics.

Our Web server software automatically logs the following information each time someone visits our website: date, time, Client IP, Server IP, web browser, URLs of page requested and referring page, among others.  We use the information gathered to help us improve our website.

## What does USD do with the personal information collected on this Web site? 

Certain personal information is used to provide information back to you, such as grades, transcripts, etc.  We do not and will not sell your personal information to anyone.  Certain postal information may be provided to our mailing service that handles the distribution of class materials and announcements.

## Is credit card / transaction information secure on this Web site? 

We care about the safety and security of your transaction. We use SSL (Secure Sockets Layer) to communicate with your browser software when you register with us online.  SSL is the industry standard security protocol, which makes it extremely difficult for anyone else to intercept your credit card or other information that you send us.

We have partnered with commercial Internet financial services such as CASHNet and Verisign to handle credit card transactions, and we do not store credit card information on USD’s servers after the transaction is processed.

## What does USD do to safeguard personal information on this site? 

We have instituted safeguards to check that our internal procedures meet our high policy standards. Only authorized employees have access to the information you provide us.

## **Internet communication security in general**

The privacy of communication over the Internet cannot be guaranteed because the Internet is not a secure medium.  USD does not assume any responsibility for any harm, loss or damage you may experience or incur by the sending of personal or confidential information over the Internet by or to USD.

## What should I do if I have questions? 

If you have questions about our privacy statement, please contact us at  1-619-260-4810.

## Consent 

By using this site, you signify your consent to USD’s online privacy statement. If you do not agree to this privacy statement, please do not use this site.  We reserve the right, at our discretion, to update, change, modify, add, or remove portions of this privacy statement from time to time.

_This Web Services Privacy and Security Statement has been developed with the recognition that Internet technologies are rapidly evolving and that underlying standard business models are still not well established. Accordingly, this statement is subject to change. Any such changes will be posted on this page._

## Reporting Copyright Infringements 

In accordance with Title II of the Digital Millennium Copyright Act (DMCA), USD has designated an agent to receive notification of a claim of copyright infringement for the University of San Diego network domain, SanDiego.edu. Please contact USD’s DMCA Designated Agent ([WebCoordinator@SanDiego.edu](mailto:WebCoordinator@SanDiego.edu)) to report a claim of copyright infringement. 

|
